Chapter 1 It
was a rainy October afternoon and I was
working in the office alone behind the
window
the rain dripped monotonously drumming
against the glass click click click I
glanced distractedly and for a moment
just for a moment I thought I saw the
face of a ghost that was spying on
me
I jumped and let out a cry for
help my
heart in my throat I looked
again but obviously I didn't see anyone so I
tried to calm down was I wrong of
course I'm so imaginative I went back to
reading but every now and then I
glanced at the window worried I had
probably worked too much
who knows maybe it was time to
go home suddenly the lights went out I
opened the desk drawer to grab
the candle I keep in case of
emergency but
I could make out something bright at the back of the
drawer what was it what was it shaking
make a trembling leg and I saw a
skull glowing in the darkness
vital jump that bolt that the chair
then ran towards the door I grabbed
the handle but noticed it was wet and sticky
I raised my leg to  observe it better in
the moonlight and when I realized
what it was it let
out a scream a
sticky liquid that looked like blood was dripping from my paw
screaming terrified I ran out into the hallway
but a blurry white shape a
ghost appeared from around a corner and a
null owl I screamed with my heart in my
throat I rushed towards the main door it
seemed to me I was living a nightmare I
ran down the dark hallway as if I
had gone mad I got to the
main door desperately but when I
tried to open it I realized it was
locked help I grabbed the handle
screaming desperately for help
I want to get out on the other side of the door
a horrible terrified meow answered
me I turned around and
ran down the hallway looking for the
emergency exit but when I turned
the corner paleness and a gloomy
phosphorescent skeleton hung from the
ceiling and raised a bony finger hello
jeroni lots of kisses or something I was about to
faint when
an idea crossed my mind that voice
that voice sounded familiar I knew it very
very  very clear it was the voice
of my trickster cousin
suddenly the light came on and a
familiar snout appeared before my nose
I don't want to be too much cousin I bet I've given you
quite a scare
chapter 2
because of my rage I was speechless
so I stuttered angrily you you you he made fun of me you you you you I
screamed
subspecies of mouse sub breed of rodent
byproduct of sewer rat how dare you
he laughed but jeroni you haven't had much
fun I exclaimed I
could have had a fit
and burst out laughing you should have
seen your face when you saw the
phosphorescent skeleton it was quite a
sight then he took
a notebook out of his pocket and with an
inspired expression scribbled some words let's see let's see let's see I
give the
phosphorescent skull a 10 with
honors to the blood dripping
from the bottle and a nice eight and a half to the
skeleton that waves instead we have to
improve the ghost isn't scary
enough the queue got ready my friend
portillo is really fried  he asked me to
help him run his new
joke shop and he was checking out the
items before putting them up for sale
then he laughed under his mustache you know it's
Halloween soon right he
lowers his voice and whispers
conspiratorially
October 31st is Halloween Halloween
me chili with my mustache buzzing with
fury I don't give a rancid cheese
Halloween I
just wanna go home I can't stand any more of
your macabre jokes and I left slamming the
door when it's too much it's too much don't you
believe
chapter 3 or forgiven I haven't introduced myself yet
my name is stilton geronimo
stilton I run the echo of the rodent the
most famous newspaper on mouse island
well as I was saying I decided to walk home
from via del tortellini
13 where I work to via del
borgo rato 8 where my house is
the walk isn't too long
when I got home I took out the key
to open the front door but
a paw as cold as ice covered my
eyes I shouted
a female voice crooned  cucu de chile what do
you have help my sister tea
exclaimed angrily jeronimo you are the
same as always I was joking you don't
have the slightest sense of humor
I jade very pale I can't take it anymore if I make it through
tomorrow it will be a miracle tea
shrugged and laughed you can't stand a
joke jeronimo then
lowered his voice and confided in me I came to
talk to you because Halloween is coming soon you
understand
I didn't even let her finish and
protested Halloween Halloween again
but it's possible that we won't talk about anything else
she insisted smoothing down her white
fur little brother I had a
brilliant idea the stilton publishing house is publishing a
book about Halloween all the tips
for preparing a party all the
tricks and special effects
you'll see it will be a success the only little problem is
that the book is very very urgent it's
more urgent so dear little
brother jeronimo much adored
my little treasure you really
I murmured suspiciously what should I do I
know my sister very well
when she's too nice
she's hiding something but she continued this you
should if my sister  she blurted it all
out you'll have to write it down and
hurry it's way faster you have
exactly 24 hours
I don't like Halloween I'm a
cowardly mouse and I don't understand anything about parties
and costumes she cut me off okay okay okay you
just need a little
goodwill besides now tricky she
works in a joke shop and you can
ask her for advice
I got upset ask her for some tricks not
in a million years not in my dreams no no
and no don't even talk about it I'll never ever and
never or I'm not called
Geronimo Stilton anymore and now Tea if you don't
mind I'm taking my leave it's been a
terrible day I wouldn't even wish a cat
goodnight and then I went into
my house and closed the door chapter 4 I
went in and hung my coat on the hanger
then I walked down the hall to the
kitchen I opened the fridge and licked my
whiskers I
think I'll try some
melted cheesecake gnaw on a piece of
cured parmesan and also some slices of
cheese ball then maybe I'll have some
ice cream  Gruyere and I had a
four cheese toast with a
lettuce leaf and lots of mayonnaise Miami
to Miami
I filled a nice glass of
gorgonzola milkshake with a triple dose of cream how
delicious I sighed I headed towards the
living room but with a shiver I
realized the light was already on
who could do that
fast as a cat I
tiptoed over and without making a sound the fire
lit in the fireplace projected
an enormous shadow against the wall I
shuddered and my whiskers trembled with
fear
I saw how the shadow grew in size my
fur stood on end I was about to
faint suddenly I heard a
familiar voice uncle uncle jeronimo suddenly I
understood the gigantic shadow
belonged to my little nephew Benjamin he
ran to me and hugged me
giving me a kiss on the tip of my
whiskers
uncle you left the door open so I
waited for you inside are you happy
uncle but why are you so pale
are you okay yes I'm fine thank you
while kicking happy uncle tea told me
aunt tea that she will write a book about
halloween can I help you how much
fun will we uncle it will be fantastic we will go
together looking for pranks at
uncle tricks' store we will invent a lot of
costumes bat vampire witch mummy
I really like parties uncle it will be
fantastic so when we started
I sighed to my favorite nephew
benjamin I can never deny him anything
chapter 5
the next morning we went to the store
where tricks worked it was called
tricks and tricks scares and her uncles I
noticed that the bell was shaped like
a skull as soon as I rang it a
tremendous scream startled me my
fur stood up and my whiskers almost fell off from the
fright
benjamin instead laughed super mouse and
coo that is a bell I know my
forehead was beaded with sweat and I tried to
gather my courage
we entered trapita's store it was
very dark and dusty as if no one
had aired it in years
and he was sitting on a stool with his
legs resting on the counter  he peeked out
from behind the old cash register
and exclaimed with satisfaction hello jeronimo you
look very pale handsome the doorbell climbs to my
eardrums at the entrance to my cousin pressed
the hidden switch of the doorbell and the
recorded scream made me jump
again
he laughed this is the scream of the mummy
but I also have the meow of the
werewolf cat the screech of the vampire and
others maybe you want to hear them no thank you
I hastened to answer laughing
under his whiskers my cousin brought me a
box with the lid closed jeronimo
want some candy open the lid and a
spring hit me right in the snout
trickster he laughed with satisfaction hahahaha I
knew that nibble aunts opened a display case
full of rubbery cheeses he held a
piece of gruyere he squashed it and the
cheese became week
trickster he took another piece and what do you say
about this mozzarella is a
perfect imitation of the real thing I said
amazed by the werewolf cat's whiskers
this mozzarella looks
real also it smells like mozzarella it is
very well limited  congratulations trapita
looked at me for a moment then
burst out laughing holding her
stomach congratulations to those who are happy is
something that always stings I mean you
jeronimo this cheese is real my
cousin lowered his voice now I'll take you to the
most secret part of the store he
made us go through a door
shaped like a cat's head and with its
jaws open even though the head was made
of papier-mâché a shiver
ran down my spine trapita spoke
in such a loud voice that I jumped come in and
see gentlemen come admire the most
mythical the most not to the most ticasual pranks
for halloween to make your
whiskers buzz with fear I looked
around us we were in a room
so dark it looked like the belly of a
hungry cat trapita made a
solemn gesture before moving on to the most exciting part
skulls bones
mummies and things like that I propose worms flies cockroaches
vermin spiders
insects hairy and not hairy fixed and
articulated plastic and rubber
big and small but all real
super unpleasant  swift as a rat he pulled
a huge sticky fly down from a shelf
and shook it buzzing at my nose he
also picked up a horrible black
hairy spider with eight legs he hung it on a
nail he snapped his fingers and the spider
quickly swung down from the thread yes it walked
sinisterly while its
red eyes lit up Benjamin was
excited look man it looks real there I
answered nervously tricky he looked for
a soft rubber worm and put it on my
nose exclaiming look a worm I
jumped back with a squeal
quickly my cousin shoved a
cockroach up the collar of my shirt
watch out for the cockroach look you have
another one here and another one here look look look
but if you have a bunch more on
you Jerome maybe you attract them by the
stench Jerome confess what sewer perfume you use
then he shoved a
rubber snake in my pocket I screamed because you
always try all the jokes on me
because you are the ideal victim Jerome you
always sting he wrapped a
rubber python around me  from the neck and exclaimed a
snake wants to strangle my cousin
Jeronimo come on scream as if it
were choking you I let out
a scream
the unpleasant softness of rubber was
pressing against my throat tricky guy dictated
notes to Benjamin to liven up the
Halloween party there can't be missing
very unpleasant rubber insects and snakes in
fact the more unpleasant and
annoying the better the better you can
find them in the store trucos y trucos miedos
y miniones which is
located on 9 Avenida del quesito
cremoso corner of requesón street
at that moment I
heard the bell ring tricky guy flew towards
the door a client I must go call me
if you need more information good
luck with the book it's more go for them
Benjamin finished taking notes Uncle
Jeronimo now we need a
costume expert immediately I called my
editorial assistant pink and pic as
always
and solves any problem on the spot
boss I'll give you the address of a chick I
met at a Halloween party
last year she wore  an exceptional costume,
absolutely exceptional, it looked
real, we've become
very good friends, call her and tell her you're coming from me